Git最强大的特性之一是创建分支的能力
One of the most powerful features of Git is the ability to create branches.
分支允许您创建不同版本的代码
The branches let you create different versions of your code
这样你就可以随意添加新功能，而不用担心搞乱什么稳定。
so that you can play around with adding new features without worrying about messing up what stable.
可以使用的最简单的命令是branch
The simplest command you can use is called branch.
它允许您查看存储库中的所有分支
It lets you take a look at all the branches in your repository.
现在 我们只有一个分支
Right now, we only have a single branch.
如果我们看一下我们的项目，点击git分支，
So if we take a look at our project and we do git branch,
您将看到我们有一个名为main的分支。
you'll see that we have a single branch called main.
通常情况下 您要做的是对现有分支进行复制
Typically what you want to do is make a copy of an existing branch.
你可以用git switch命令来完成。
You can do that with thee git switch command.
它将具有与当前分支相同的历史
It'll have the same history as the current branch.
这个命令有一个稍微老一点的版本，叫做git checkout，你可能在很多例子中看到过，
There's a slightly older version of this command called git checkout, and you may see that in a lot of examples,
注意，对于git checkout，你必须执行git checkout - b，然后是你想要创建的新分支的名称。
notice that with git checkout, you have to do git checkout minus b, and then the name of the new branch that you want to create.
而对于git switch，它是git switch - c，然后是名称。
Whereas with git switch, its git switch minus c and then the name.
让我们继续在我们的项目中这样做
Let's go ahead and do that in our project.
所以在我的项目中，我注意到我有一些额外的类，我想摆脱。
So in my project, I've noticed that I have a few additional classes that I want to git rid of.
例如，我有这个site-header类。
So, e.g. I have this site-header class.
我创建这个小网站的方法是从之前的一个项目中复制东西，
And the way that I created this small website was by copying things from a previous project,
我忘了去掉site-header标签和site-nav标签，还有family-sans类。
and I forgot to take away the site-header tag as well as this site-nav tag, and also this family-sans class.
其他的都是一个引导类，这些只是我在之前的项目中添加的额外类，
Everything else is a bootstrap class, and these are just extra classes that I had added in a previous project,
所以我要创建一个新的分支来处理这些事情。
so I'm going to create a new branch to take care of those things.
让我们继续执行git switch -c，我把这个分支命名为fix-classes。
Let's go ahead and issue a git switch minus c, and I'll call this branch fix-classes.
现在，注意到它说它切换到一个新的分支，
Now, notice that it said that it switched to a new branch,
如果我执行git status，它会显示我现在在分支fix-classes上。
and if I do a git status, it'll show me that I'm now on branch fix-classes.
对吧?为了应对这些不同的变化，
Right? To take care of these different changes,
我要做的是搜索并替换所有的文件。
what I'm going to do is do a search and replace so that I change all the files.
有人复制了这个site-header，我在VSCode中，
Someone a copy this site-header, and I'm in VSCode here,
所以我可以在这里执行替换文件命令，
so I can do a replace in files command right here,
它会找到side-header并用空替换它。
and it's going to find side-header and replace it with nothing.
点击这个按钮 它会替换所有有这个类的文件
So we'll hit this button right here, and it's going to replace all the files that have that class.
我将在这个family sans中对site-nav做同样的事情。
And I'll do the same thing with site-nav in this family-sans.
再一次，我将把这段文字替换为空。
Once again, I'll take this text and replace it with nothing.
我点击这个按钮，
so I'll click on this button right here,
它将替换三个文件中的所有内容。
it's going to replace everything in three files.
这就是我所需要做的
That's all I need to do.
让我们清除这些，看看状态
So let's go ahead and let's clear this out and take a look at the status
它在给我看那些文件。
it's showing me those files.
如果我愿意，我可以在git选项卡中预览更改，
If I wanted to, I can preview the changes here in the git tab,
这样我就可以查看每一个文件，看看这些修改是在哪里进行的。
so I can take a look at each one of those files and see where those changes were made.
在我看来一切都很好 所以我要添加并提交这些更改
Everything looks good to me, so I'm going to add and commit these changes.
我们把这个擦掉
So let's go ahead and clear this out.
好了，现在，如果我做一个git日志，它会告诉我，我在这里添加了一个新的提交。
All right, so now, if I do a git log, it tells me that I have added this new commit here.
它还告诉我main仍然处于原来的状态。
And it's also telling me that main is still in this old state.
它会注意到我在这个新分支中做了一个提交，但我没有将它添加到main中。
So it's actually noticed that I've done a commit here in this new branch, but I haven't added it into main.
现在我们已经准备好同步我们在新分支和主分支中所做的事情了，
So now that we're ready to synchronize what we're doing in our new branch with our main branch,
将需要了解合并。
will need to know about merging.
merge命令将把一个分支中的更改合并到当前分支中。
The merge command will merge the changes from one branch into the current branch.
它是这样的。
And it looks like this.
该命令将把我在这里指定的分支的合并更改为当前分支。
This command will change the merges from the branch I specify right here into the current branch.
所以在我们的例子中 我们必须切换回主分支 然后执行这个命令
So in our case, we have to switch back into the main branch and then execute this command.
让我们在我们的项目中这样做。
so let's go ahead and do that with our project.
我们把这个擦掉。我们将执行git switch main。
let's clear this out. We'll do a git switch main.
现在我们在主分支，
Now we're in the main branch,
然后输入git branch，我们可以看到这里有两个分支。
and let's do git branch So we can see that we have two branches right here.
我们要做的就是使用git merge，然后添加fix-classes分支。
And so what we'll do is use git merge and we'll add the fix-classes branch.
现在 我们将新分支的所有更改添加到主分支中
Now this is added all of the changes from our new branch into the main branch.
清除这个，如果我执行git log online，你会在主分支上看到这个新提交。
Clear this out, and if I do a git log oneline, you'll see that new commit right here on the main branch.
现在 我还有另一个分支
Now, I still have the other branch.
因此，当您完成了一个特性或修复后，删除不再需要的分支是一个好主意。
So when you're done with a feature or a fix, it's a good idea to delete the branch that you no longer need.
要做到这一点，你可以执行git分支，然后，使用delete选项，指定要删除的分支的名称。
to do that, You can execute the git branch, and then, with the delete option, specify the name of the branch that you want to delete.
有几个选择。你可以用这个- d选项。
There's a couple of options. You can use this minus d option.
只要分支没有冲突，- d就会迫使git忽略其他内容，直接删除分支。
As long as the branches are free of conflicts, the minus d forces git to ignore things and just delete the branch.
好了，我们把这些擦掉，
ok let's go ahead and clear this out,
我们将删除固定类。
and we'll delete fix-classes.
所以我有时会这样做，我忘记做git分支，然后- d，然后fix-classes。
So I do this sometimes I forgot to do the git branch and then minus d and then fix-classes.
对吧 所以它删除了那个分支
Right? So it deleted that branch.
我们把这个清除掉，然后执行git branch，这里只有一个分支。
let's clear this out, and we'll do git branch Now, there's only one branch.
这一系列的操作就是我们所说的git流。
This sequence of doing things is what we call git flow.
你创建一个新的分支，通常是一个特性或一个修复分支，
You create a new branch, that's usually a feature or a fix branch,
你对那个分支进行修改，然后把那个分支合并回主分支，然后删除旧分支。
you make changes to that branch, then you merge that branch back to master, and then you delete the old branch.
这就是开发人员在实际项目中的工作方式
This is how developers work on real projects.
现在 每个公司都有不同的版本 但它遵循这个一般模式
Now, every company has a different version of this, but it follows this general pattern.
当你与其他人合作时 每个人都离开主分支
When you collaborate with other people, everyone leaves the main branch alone.
你可以看到，如果每个人都试图在同一个分支上工作，事情会变得非常混乱。
You can see that things would git really messy if everybody was trying to work on the same branch.
所以每个人都创建一个新的分支 然后你做出改变 然后你遵循这个结构
So everybody creates a new branch, then you make a change, and you follow this structure.
这将使与他人合作变得容易得多
This will make working with others a lot easier.